Woo Woo Woo Yeah,
yeah,
yeah That is an eastern diamondback rattlesnake And it's not even dead
Oh, wow Bro,
you call that a bite?
That doesn't even hurt.
This snake is massive.
Calm down.
Whoa
Can you see that?
Oh I got him Oh,
my gosh That was incredible
Oh Yes My name's David Oren.
I do something called herping.
It's kind of a slang term for herpetology.
which is the study of reptiles and amphibians.
This is the series where you take a bite from a snake and rank the pain on a scale of 1 to 10.
I have a social media following in the past 6 months,
7 months,
kind of grown up.
Praise God
Praise God Praise God Praise God,
that is so cool.
My ultimate fundamental identity before anything else is the fact that I am a servant of Christ.
You love the creation.
What about the creator?
Do you love the creator?
Do you know the mind of God who created this entire cosmos and who created you?
There we go,
a few strikes there.
Not terrible.
I want to somehow present God's creation and use it as a platform for the gospel.
The Christian Steve Irwin,
it would not be a bad title,
as long as the Christian part comes first.
Where's everything at Wings?
I still work full time at a pizza shop.
Newberry Pizza at Wings,
I've never got that much love before.
Hey,
you throw me a ranch.
Thank you.
And that's a great little job because it allows me to...
Boss is really flexible and stuff.
I can go out and look for snakes and sort of make my content just throughout my normal work week.
I'll be back in 30-ish minutes,
depending on herping.
Maybe 40,
we'll see.
Take the long way to make sure we get maximum snake cruising time.
So we are in Newberry,
Florida.
Since 13,
I've lived right outside of Gainesville.
Man,
we got all sorts of habitat out here.
Where we're going right now,
actually in this delivery,
we're going through some absolutely phenomenal scrub habitat,
some of the best North Florida has to offer.
This is me being nerdy about herping.
So last year I kept record of everything.
We got eight eastern mud snakes,
five Florida pine snakes,
five diamondback rattlesnakes.
135 cottonmouths,
that was the most common snake out of everything.
I've only ever been bitten by one venomous snake,
a dusky pygmy rattlesnake.
But yeah,
just kind of like a throbbing pain,
nothing too bad.
And all my DORs,
in her terminology,
DOR stands for dead on road.
So when I find a road-kill snake,
it's a DOR.
I got a bunch of crushing DORs,
man,
it was so sad.
No
When you do a herping,
there's like three main modes.
You can do road cruising,
which is what I do,
where you just sort of cruise around in good habitat.
And then there's hiking,
which I do pretty frequently as well.
And then there's flipping,
where you like lay out either artificial cover,
like pieces of board and tin,
or just,
you know,
natural stuff like logs and rocks.
You flip it over,
sometimes you can find a snake underneath.
But the downside of cruising,
which is what I love doing,
is you come across a lot of DORs.
I've been on Instagram.
Forever,
whether that's catching snakes on my story or writing poetry and doing all that kind of stuff.
But
I've had in my mind,
I want to be a
YouTuber.
I want to do an animal catching thing.
I want to somehow present
God's creation.
And I don't know,
like I have like a perfectionist mindset sometimes.
I wanted to have a YouTube channel.
I wanted to have it perfect,
just,
you know,
looking amazing.
I felt I wasn't able to deliver on that.
I had insecurities with the way I presented myself.
I felt awkward still and wasn't really comfortable in my own skin sometimes.
And then
May rolled around of 2020.
A car broke down.
I delivered pizza in and I was out of work for like two weeks.
And I was like,
well,
put this time to good use.
Let me start working on TikTok videos.
I caught a black racer.
It bit me.
I said,
ow,
I did like a little funny video.
Ow,
It went viral overnight.
I posted it the next day and it went viral overnight.
I think it ended up getting over 9 million views.
And
I garnered probably
20,000 followers from that first video.
And from there,
I just kept posting.
I think this might be our house.
Here is that delicious food.
Just a second.
Hey,
how you doing,
boss?
I ain't no good at all.
How about you?
No,
ain't no good at all.
Why is that?
I'm just old.
Uh-oh.
What's wrong with being old?
There's not as much gold in these golden years as I thought there would be.
Are you in Christ,
brother?
Do you know the Lord Jesus?
Absolutely.
Hey,
then every single day you're closer to getting to see him in person,
right?
The atypic vision.
Come on,
Edgar.
Get in this house.
Keep on running the race,
brother.
I appreciate it,
all right?
Absolutely.
You've got to.
Amen.
Have a good day.
What a sweet little couple,
man.
I want to show you a tip.
$5.
Yes,
sir.
Look at that habitat.
That is incredible.
Oh,
my goodness.
Where did he go?
It was just a little skink.
Nothing too interesting,
but I don't usually see skinks sitting out on the road.
I'm not really sure what he was doing.
Where you at,
buddy?
Ah,
it was weird.
I never cruise skinks,
ever.
It's like a little shiny lizard.
Not a snake,
so it doesn't matter.
Sometimes a day or two will go by and I won't be able to find a snake.
And I definitely start to feel like,
man,
like I gotta get content.
I just really want to find another snake again,
but...
I just gotta trust the Lord with it.
I'll find a snake when he wants me to,
and I won't when he doesn't want me to,
so.
See me?
I just waved to you.
Oh,
no,
I didn't see you.
I'm coming.
What's up,
Kay?
You got your snake hook?
You're flipping stuff?
Nice.
The most important thing is the sun's not gonna break through through the clouds for the next few hours,
though.
So this is actually a good time.
Oh there's two tortoises.
Oh no,
they're turtles.
They're not tortoises,
they're actual turtles.
What?
That's a chicken turtle.
Grab that guy.
That one's really cool.
Let me see,
let me see.
Okay,
it's urinating like a lot.
Let me see it.
Get it all out.
We're still going.
Yeah,
they're kind of chill.
Maybe they were trying to cross or something.
They shouldn't bite me.
Or she.
Yeah.
These guys are cool,
but they're not snakes.
I need to get them to water though.
I don't feel comfortable leaving them in the road here.
I don't really know whose property this is,
but they won't mind us using their pond,
I'm sure.
Okay,
he put this one over there too.
Thanks.
Look at this guy here.
Wait,
Kayla,
hold this real fast.
He's trying to go ham on me.
Ready?
Ow
Doesn't hurt too bad.
Kind of like something of a sharp beak,
but bite me for the people.
Bite me for the people.
I realize that you have to have a little tiny bit of sensationalism,
sensationalization.
in order to get people interested in reptiles and amphibians.
My name is David Ward,
and this is the series where you take a snake bite and break it on a scale of one to ten.
Right there,
yeah.
Work those teeth in.
Wow Honestly,
just not that bad.
I definitely received some pushback from the herping community just because there's not really herping influencers.
I would be one of the few people that someone would actually bring the name herping into the modern vernacular.
But I know there's one herp in particular who's very...
respected,
probably the best herper in the community.
He has spoken to me before and says that he doesn't like the fact,
but I'll use sensationalism in any of my content,
actually.
He thinks that a snake shouldn't have to bite someone to get people's attention.
And I actually completely agree with him.
I don't think there needs to be any sort of snake biting here,
running after and grabbing it there.
People should just be able to go and appreciate and see the beauty and wonder of snakes for what they are.
They're amazing as they are.
But they don't.
I don't know.
It's frustrating.
It's actually been really hard at some point having the community.
Look down to me and make fun of me and stuff,
but it's fine.
I'm vindicated before God and my friends and stuff who love me,
so it's alright.
If we get an Eastern Ironman battle snake,
I'll flip out,
man.
I'll be so excited.
Ah,
I'm excited.
Diamondback battle snakes like to sit at the base of these palm fronds.
None of that one.
It could happen guys.
You get a pine snake right here just
BAM sitting out.
Or a fence lizard.
I'll catch that if I can.
Don't be scared.
I don't want to hurt you.
It's just a female so not gonna have the incredible blue all over but she does have a nice bit of blue right there under her chin.
She's wiggling.
Let me go.
I didn't do anything wrong.
So we'll let you go in a second.
Let me take a picture for Instagram.
Come on coach.
Come on racer.
Where y'all hiding at?
Why are y'all hiding at?
No snakes.
There's snakes under here guys.
No.
Where are the snakes?
Come on Lord,
give us a snake.
Yes Praise God Check this out guys.
Praise God guys.
What's up?
I got exciting news.
Did you know that when you become a Christian,
God transfers you from the domain of darkness and into the kingdom of his Son,
Jesus Christ,
in whom we have redemption and forgiveness of sins?
Get to know the Son of God on an intimate level.
Of course,
you know,
a lot of people in the herping community could care less about whether or not preaching the gospel,
but we're on the same side when it comes to conservation and preservation,
and people will comment straight up sometimes,
we're done with the religion,
you know,
how about you post in the video you're getting bit by a snake?
You know,
I get it.
Apostle Paul talks about how
Jesus is an offensive person to the unbeliever,
and I understand why.
I mean,
it's,
what's more offensive than telling someone,
you're a broken,
sinful person,
and you need Jesus to come into your life and put you back together.
So,
I definitely receive a lot of pushback for that at times.
I'm so thankful for people who just put up with it and continue to follow me anyways.
Hopefully seeds are being planted in that process.
There's a lot of people here tonight,
Everybody's kind of showing up late.
I'm glad I'm not the only one.
We are in Claremont,
Florida.
This is New Wave Church.
This is actually called ROW.
This is our young adult group.
So many people here,
so on fire for Christ at such a young age.
It's really fantastic.
If you don't know Christ and you want to know Him,
tonight is your opportunity.
Don't leave this place the same way they...
You say it's a hospital,
it's more like a military hospital because there's a battle going on.
There's a war going on for each and every single one of your lives.
It's true.
Honestly,
who are you going to tell about Jesus when you leave here?
That's it.
Oh,
I'm facing all my demons and hoping I can find the words to say.
I had no real knowledge of David.
I've seen some social media stuff,
honestly.
I was like,
that's the guy that lets snakes bite him.
You know what?
I want to be friends with him.
The temptation of social media,
it comes down to the person that you are because they see the celebrities and it's like,
you know what,
I want to be like that.
But they only see the Snapchat filter of their life.
What you're doing,
it's like,
you are a small speck of just a vessel of what...
God is using you to do.
Yes,
absolutely.
There's definitely a temptation that comes with being on social media.
To begin with,
I've always struggled,
even before I had a following,
of being conceited or prideful or arrogant and thinking of myself more highly than I ought.
Pride has always just been a particular sin of mine that I've fought against and struggled with.
I don't know,
it's definitely a challenge.
I think to myself,
man,
I struggle with lust.
I struggle with the temptation of pornography and masturbation.
So it's not something I completely beat yet.
You know,
when you have followers,
the temptations for that,
they arise.
I have girls who message me from time to time,
and the temptation's there.
And there is a fear that if the temptations keep coming,
what if I,
like King David,
fall prey to it?
I remember I posted about it recently in a very severe way.
I talked about point blank,
my struggle with masturbation,
in a little poem or something I'd written about working through it one night.
Most of the people in my comments were just in there.
tearing me apart.
Progressive liberal Christians,
actually,
which I didn't even expect were just all over me about that.
Flip that,
though,
I had so many other believers coming out and saying,
wow,
this is so encouraging.
I don't know why we as Christians feel like we can't talk about this in the church.
Why does this have to be silent?
It's the most liberating thing to know
Jesus has paid for this sin that I have committed of masturbation and pornography.
He's paid for it full.
I am forgiven.
I'm redeemed.
And so far the Lord has been so faithful to me and given me strength I don't deserve and kept me from that.
It's all his doing,
none of my own.
Alright,
Kaylee just spotted a little cottonmouth.
That was perfect.
We just can't let it get away.
I got my hook.
I'm going to figure out how to do this.
Come here,
buddy.
come here.
Watch out,
Dang it,
that's frustrating.
I almost had him.
You know,
it's interesting because as a
Reformed evangelical,
there's a belief that if you believe in the Bible,
you don't believe in science.
And that's not at all true.
And the reason why is because if something is true,
truly true in Scripture,
then it's not going to be false in science.
If it's truly true in science,
it's not going to be false in scripture.
That being said,
I would consider myself a creationist.
I look at the arguments that certain creationists present.
I'm not sure I'm persuaded of all of them,
but I do believe the word of God when it talks about a young earth.
I believe the earth is 6,000 years old.
That's French.
People love hearing that.
That's crazy.
Because of that,
I run into the difficult problem of,
well,
you know,
what if somehow we could somehow demonstrably prove there's no way that
Science and scripture could both be compatible.
That would absolutely be a crisis of worldview for me.
I don't want to believe
Christianity. I don't want to believe in God,
if there is no God.
If God's not real,
why am I still a virgin?
why am I not going out and living my life the way I want to live it?
I don't want to be a Christian if it's a false religion,
right?
Flip that log.
You never know.
I wish it had happened.
I'm sure there's snakes out here,
I just don't know where they are.
David,
do you need this little pine?
I have my pine snake.
I would never.
I would never do that.
Not gonna sell my soul.
Herping is real.
You don't find stuff sometimes.
On my left.
Oh wait,
snake.
Come here.
It is a Florida Banded Water Snake.
Just a harmless little guy.
So make sure we grab him here without letting him get away.
Come here buddy.
Okay.
And he is skinny and emaciated,
but it is a snake.
So,
that's what we've been looking for in the last day and a half.
You're it buddy.
You're the snake for the video.
How's it make you feel?
Ah.
I think he has like a disease.
His eye is all crusted over.
What a guy,
man.
Check it out,
guys.
We finally got ourselves a snake.
It is the crustiest little Nerodia.
Poor guy,
emaciated little guy that you could ever imagine.
This is it,
man.
This is his shot at the spotlight.
What a beautiful creature.
That's what happens.
You just kind of scan with your eyes at all times,
and you're just always registering for a snake shape.
And there he was,
just sitting here,
right back where he found you.
God is so good towards his creation with so much we don't deserve,
and it's a wonderful thing.
I would definitely say some of the ways I most authentically worship Christ is when I'm out there appreciating his creation.
What is next for me?
I don't know what the Lord has in store,
but
I would love to continue pursuing the social media following.
I mean,
I love my job at Newberry Pizza,
man.
But,
you know,
I've been there three years now.
If I could travel the world full time,
doing what I love,
going around,
catching snakes in different areas,
and preaching Christ through God's creation in different areas,
it would be a dream come true.
Have some exciting stuff under wraps.
Maybe I'll get a TV show soon with someone.
Can I put out my merch soon?
I don't know.
The future is looking very bright right now.
I don't know what the Lord has in store for me,
so...